University of Connecticut, Office of Institutional Research Records 1998.0288
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
University of Connecticut, Office of Institutional Research Records
1950, 1960-2001
1998.0288
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
48.1 Linear feet
The Office of Institution Research collection contains the administrative records, financial records, publications, correspondence, reports, and clippings of the Office of Institutional Research(OIR). The mission of the Office of Institutional Research is to provide data and analysis to support the management, planning, evaluation and assessment functions of the University. The office fulfills this mission in a variety of ways and serves a wide range of "consumers" of information, both internal and external to the University. Some of the data categories include: Student enrollment data, UConn fact books, Alumni data, Faculty and staff data, Degrees conferred data, Teaching evaluation information, Annual report information, and University Metrics.
Office of Institutional Research
History
The University of Connecticut Office of Institutional Research provides data and analysis to support the management, planning, evaluation and assessment functions of the University. The office fulfills this mission in a variety of ways and serves a wide range of consumers of information, both internal and external to the University.
The Office of Institutional Research has a university-wide approach to data collection, data reporting and data analysis. The Office is interested in both the whole of the University of Connecticut, including the Health Center for certain summary counts of students and staff, and all the parts comprising that whole.
The level of analysis and the timeliness of the response to data questions provided by the Office of Institutional Research are largely dependent upon the sources and types of data available. The Office works with all types of data: raw data on individual records; aggregate raw data; data that must be transferred from one format to another, or from hand-calculated worksheets into computer spreadsheets; data that must be first collected or compiled from surveys or various printed sources and then put into a computerized format; data readily accessible through administrative disks; and data in computer files with unique formats, data dictionaries, and storage considerations. Typically multiple sources of data are used, including non-computerized data, to answer questions.
The Office of Institutional Research consists primarily of data users, data analysts, and data presenters. The Office does not view itself as a data maintainer, however, in reality, they edit and maintain data perceived to be important to the University but which is not being edited or maintained by other administrative offices. Historically, the Office of Institutional Research has been involved in such things as legislative bill tracking until an Office of Governmental Relations was created. Additionally, the Office has been involved in space utilization studies until the responsibility was moved to the Office of Facilities. The individual staff data published in the University staff directory was handled in the Office until Human Resources took over the task. Currently the Office of Institutional Research maintains data collection as well as reporting systems for; student ratings of faculty; opinions of college experiences by undergraduate alumni; academic progress tracking of student intercollegiate athletes; data to support the University budget-making process, including mission statements; University program measures for the State's Office Policy and Management and the Governor's Budget; University Program Assessment; Faculty and staff data reporting; and Student data analysis and reporting.
Scope and Content
The collection contains the research and documentation of the Office of Institutional Research at the University of Connecticut. Materials in the collection include administrative records, clippings, correspondence, fliers, notes, and publications related to the Office of Institutional Research from the years 1988 to 2000.
The records contain the departmental annual reports and executive summaries from the fiscal years of 1989-1995 and 1997-2000. Some of the many subjects discussed in the collection include aerospace studies, agriculture and natural resources, anthropology, the U.S. Army, central mail service, counseling program for intercollegiate athletes, ecology and evolutionary biology, educational innovation, engineering, extended and continuing education, family studies, fine arts, geology and geophysics, Jorgensen Center for the Performing Arts, the regional campuses, The William Benton Museum of Art, public and urban affairs, the Homer Babbidge Library, The Roper Center for Public Opinion Research, the Ratcliffe Hicks School of Agriculture, the U.S. Air Force, and the Veteran's Center at the university.
Publications in the collection include the American Council on Education, Educational Record: The Magazine of Higher Education, the University of Connecticut Fact Book, and The University of Connecticut Chronicle.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Provenance and Acquisition
The records of the Office of Institutional Research have been transferred periodically to the University Archives beginning in 1998.
Administrative Records.; Correspondence.; Financial Records.; Fliers. [printed matter]; Minutes.; Publications.; School Records.
- Series I: An Inventory, 1950, 1960-2001; 37.0 Linear feet
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, notes, 1988-1989; 1.0 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs in alphabetical order (Box 1998.0288_1)
    Scope and Content Note
    Subjects include: Departmental annual reports and executive summaries from fiscal year 1989 (Academic Programs, Aerospace Studies, Agriculture and Natural Resources, Anthropology, Army, Business and Administration, Central Mail Service, Chemistry, Computer Center, Communication Sciences, Counseling Program for Intercollegiate Athletes, Ecology and Evolutionary Biology, Education, Educational Innovation, Engineering, English, Extended and Continuing Education, Family Studies, Fine Arts, General Information, Geography, Geology and Geophysics, Graduate School, UConn Advance).
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, notes, 1988-1989; 1.0 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs in alphabetical order (Box 1998.0288_2)
    Subjects include: Departmental annual reports and executive summaries from fiscal year 1989 (Hartford Campus, History, Honors Programs, International Students and Scholars, Instructional Media and Technology, Jorgensen, Journalism, Latin American and Caribbean Studies, Law, Liberal Arts and Sciences, Library, Linguistics, Marine Sciences, Materials Science, Mathematics, Modern and Classical Languages, Molecular and Cell Biology, Nursing, Facilities, Oral History, Personnel, Pharmacy, Philosophy, Physiology and Neurobiology, Political Science, Psychology, Public and Urban Affairs, Registrar, Regional Campuses, Research Foundation, Small Business Development Center, Social Inquiry, Social Work, Sociology, Statistics, Stamford Campus, Student Affairs and Services, Study Abroad Programs, Technical Services Center, Torrington Campus, Water Resources, The William Benton Museum of Art, Women's Center, Women's Studies).
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, notes, 1989-1990; 1.0 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs in alphabetical order (Box 1998.0288_3)
    Subjects include: Departmental annual reports and executive summaries from fiscal year 1990 (Aerospace Studies, African American Cultural Center, African American Studies, Agriculture and Natural Resources, Business and Administration, Computer Center, Education, Engineering, Extended and Continuing Education, Family Studies, Fine Arts, General Funds and Tuition Fund, Graduate School, Hartford Campus, Health Center, Higher Education, Honors Program, Institutional Research, Instructional Media and Technology, International Affairs, Law, Library, Marital and Family Therapy, Materials Science)
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, notes, 1989-1990, 1990-1991; 1.0 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs in alphabetical order within fiscal year (Box 1998.0288_4)
    Subjects include: Departmental annual reports and executive summaries from fiscal year 1990 (Oral History, Pathobiology, Pharmacy, Physiology and Neurobiology, Political Science, Public and Urban Affairs, Registrar, Research Foundation, Social Work, Stamford Campus, Transportation, Traveler's Center, Technical Services Center, Waterbury Campus, The William Benton Museum of Art, Women's Center, Women's Studies), departmental annual reports and executive summaries from fiscal year 1991 (Academic Programs, Aetna Chair of Writing, African American Studies, Avery Point Campus, Chemical Engineering, Civil Engineering, Computer Center, Computer Science and Engineering, Counseling Program for Intercollegiate Athletes, Electrical Systems Engineering, Environmental Research, Extended and Continuing Education, Grinding Research and Development, Hartford Campus, Homer Babbidge Library, Honors Program, Instructional Media and Technology, Materials Science, Mechanical Engineering, Metallurgy, Minority Engineering, Modern and Classical Languages, Public and Urban Affairs, Registrar, Research and Computing, Research Foundation, Scheduling Office, Social Inquiry and The Roper Center for Public Opinion Research, Stamford Campus, Taylor Booth Center, Technical Services Center, Torrington Campus, Undergraduate Program, Waterbury Campus, The William Benton Museum of Art, Women's Center, Women's Studies).
  - Administratice records, correspondence, notes, 1991-1992; 1.0 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs in alphabetical order (Box 1998.0288_5)
    Subjects include: Departmental annual reports and executive summaries from fiscal year 1992 (Academic Programs, Admissions, Aetna Chair of Writing, Affirmative Action Program, African American Studies, Agricultural and Resource Economics, Agricultural Experiment Station, Agricultural Publications, Agriculture and Natural Resources, Agriculture (Ratcliffe Hicks School of), Air Force, Alumni Relations, Animal Genetics, Animal Science, Annual Report Informatin, Anthropology, Athletics, Biology Central Services, Budget, Bursar, Business and Administration, Career Programs, Chemistry, Communication Sciences, Community School of Art, Cooperative Extension System, Counseling Program for Intercollegiate Athletes, Counseling Service, Credit Programs, Ecology and Evolutionary Biology, Economic Education, Economics, Education, Engineering, English, Extended and Continuing Education, External Relations, Facilities Management, Farm and Service, Finance and Administration, Financial Aid, Fine Arts, Food Services).
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, notes, 1991-1992; 1.0 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs in alphabetical order (Box 1998.0288_6)
    Subjects include: Departmental annual reports and executive summaries from fiscal year 1992 (Geography, Geology and Geophysics, Graduate School, Grants and Contractors, Hartford Campus, Health Center, Health Services, History, Homer Babbidge Library, Honors Programs, Information Services, Instructional Media and Technology, International Affairs, Jorgensen, Journalism, Labor Education, Latin American and Caribbean Studies, Liberal Arts and Sciences, Linguistics, Mail Services, Marine Sciences, Materials Science, Mathematics, Microchemistry Laboratory, Modern and Classical Languages, Molecular and Cell Biology, Natural Resources Management and Engineering, Nursing, Nutritional Science, Pathobiology, Payroll, Personnel, Pharmacy, Philosophy, Physics, Physiology and Neurobiology, Plant Science, Police Department, Political Science, Poultry Farm, Professional Education, Psychology, Public Relations, Public Service, Purchasing, Regional Campus Summaries, Registrar, Research Foundation, Residential Life, The Roper Center for Public Opinion, Small Business Development Center, Social Work, Sociology, Stamford Campus, Statistics, Student Affairs (and Services), Student Commissaries, Technical Services Center, Torrington Campus, Women's Center, Women's Studies).
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, 1992-1993; 1.0 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs in alphabetical order (Box 1998.0288_7)
    Subjects include: Departmental annual reports and executive summaries from fiscal year 1993 (Agriculture and Natural Resources, Agriculture (Ratcliffe Hicks School of), Air Force, Allied Health Professions, Anthropology, Biology Central Services, Business and Administration, Chemistry, Communication Sciences, Computer Center, Cooperative Extension System, Counseling Program for Intercollegiate Athletes, Ecology and Evolutionary Biology, Economics, Education, Engineering, English, European Studies, Extended and Continuing Education,Family Studies, Fine Arts, Geography, Geology and Geophysics, Graduate School, Hartford Campus, History, Homer Babbidge Library, Honors Programs, Instructional Media and Technology, International Affairs, Journalism, Latin American and Caribbean Studies, Law, Liberal Arts and Sciences, Linguistics).
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, publications, 1992-1993, 1993-1994; 1.0 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs in alphabetical order within fiscal year (Box 1998.0288_8)
    Subjects include: Departmental annual reports and executive summaries from fiscal year 1993 (Marine Sciences, Materials Science, Mathematics, Minority Services, Modern and Classical Languages, Molecular and Cell Biology, Oral History, Pharmacy, Philosophy, Physics, Physiology and Neurobiology, Political Science, "A Portrait of Our Progress", Pre Medical and Pre Dental, Psychology, Puerto Rican and Latin American Cultural Center, Research Foundation, Small Business Development Center, Social Work, Sociology, Stamford Campus, Technical Services Center, Women's Studies), departmental annual reports and executive summaries from fiscal year 1994 (Academic Programs, African American Cultural Center, Agricultural Experiment Station, Agriculture and Natural Resources, Agriculture (Ratcliffe Hicks School of), Agriculture and Resource Economics, Air Force, Allied Health Professions, Animal Genetics, Anthropology, Asian American Studies, Biology Central Services, Business and Administration, Chemistry, Communication Sciences, Computer Center, Cooperative Extension System, Counseling Program for Intercollegiate Athletes, Ecology and Evolutionary Biology, Economics, Education, Engineering, English, Environmental Health and Safety, Extended and Continuing Education).
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, fliers, notes, publications, 1993-1994, 1994-1995; 1.0 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs in alphabetical order within fiscal year (Box 1998.0288_9)
    Subjects include: Departmental annual reports and executive summaries from fiscal year 1994 (Family Studies, Fine Arts, Food Marketing Policy Center, Geography, Geology and Geophysics, Graduate School, Hartford Campus, History, Honors Programs, Instructional Media and Technology, International Affairs, Journalism, Labor Education, Latin American Studies, Liberal Arts and Sciences, Library (Homer Babbidge), Linguistics, Marine Sciences, Mathematics, Modern and Classical Languages, Molecular Cell Biology, Museum of Art (William Benton), Museum of Natural History, Natural Resources Management and Engineering, Nursing, Nutritional Science, Pathobiology, Pharmacy, Philosophy, Physics, Physiology and Neurobiology, Plant Science, Political Science, Pre Medical and Pre Dental, Psychology, Public Service International, Registrar, Research Foundation, Social Work, Sociology, Stamford Campus, Technical Services Center, Waterbury Campus, Women's Center, Women's Studies), departmental annual reports and executive summaries from fiscal year 1995 (Academic Programs, Accounting, Accounts Payable, Aerospace Studies, African American Cultural Center, African American Studies, Agriculture (Ratcliffe Hicks School of), Agriculture and Natural Resources, Allied Health Professions, Alumni Relations, Animal Science, Annual Report to State, Anthropology, Asian American Cultural Center, Asian American Studies, Avery Point Campus, Biology Central Services, Bursar, Business).
  - Administrative records, correspondence, publications, 1994-1995; 1.0 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs in alphabetical order (Box 1998.0288_10)
    Subjects include: Departmental annual reports and executive summaries from fiscal year 1995 (Chemistry, Civil and Environmental Engineering, Communication Sciences, Computer Center, Cooperative Extension System, Counseling Program for Intercollegiate Athletes, Ecology and Evolutionary Biology, Economics, Education, English, Extended and Continuing Education, Family Studies, Finance and Business Affairs, Financial Planning and Budgeting, Financial Aid and Student Employment, Fine Arts, Foundation, Geography, Geology and Geophysics, Governmental Relations, Graduate School, Grants and Contract Administration, Hartford Campus, History, Honors Program, Individualized Major Program, Instructional and Media Technology, International Affairs, Journalism, Labor Education Center, Latin American and Caribbean Studies, Liberal Arts and Sciences, Linguistics, Libraries, Marine Sciences, Marine Science and Technology Center, Materials Science, Mathematics, Mechanical Engineering, Molecular and Cell Biology, Museum of Art (William Benton), Natural Resources Management and Engineering, Nursing, Oral History, Pathobiology, Payroll, Pharmacy, Physics, Philosophy, Physiology and Neurobiology, Plant Science, Political Science, Pre Medical and Pre Dental, Psychology, Public and Urban Affairs, Puerto Rican/Latin American Cultural Center, Puerto Rican and Latino Studies, Purchasing, Relations, Research Foundation, Social Inquiry/The Roper Center, Social Work, Sociology, Stamford Campus, Statistics, Student Affairs, Technical Services, Torrington Campus, Waterbury Campus, Women's Center).
  - Administrative records, correspondence, notes, 1968-1973, 1978-1989; 1.0 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs in chronological order by fiscal year (Box 1998.0288_11)
    Subjects include: Annual reports from the Division of Student Affairs and Services (Activities Coordinator, Admissions, Assistant Vice President, Associate Dean (Office of the), Associate Dean of Student Affairs, Associated Student Commissary, Career Services, Cooperative Education and Off-campus, Counseling Services, Counseling and Student Development, Counseling and Student Testing, Dean (Office of the), Employment, Financial Aid, Fiscal Management, Food Services, Health Services, Men's Affairs, Minority Student Affairs, Orientation Services, Patricio Affair, Placement (and Career Planning), Program Evaluation and Research, Public Health Servies (Coordinator of), Registrar, Residential Life, Special Academic and Enrichment Affairs, Special Academic and Enrichment Programs, Special Programs, Special Student Services, Student Activities/Union Programs, Student Affairs, Student Aid, Student Commissaries, Student Data Systems (and Programming), Student Personnel, Student Union, Summer Program, Veteran's Center, Vice President (Office of the), Women's Affairs).
  - Administrative records, 1989-1997; 1.0 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs in chronological order by fiscal year (Box 1998.0288_12)
    Subjects include: Annual reports from the Division of Student Affairs and Services (Admissions, Career Services, Community Outreach (Center for), Cooperative Education and Off-campus, Counseling Services, Day of Pride Scholarship, Dining Services, Employment, Fiscal Management, Food Services, Greek Life (Office of), Health Services, Long Range Planning, Orientation Services, Planning and Assessment, Residential Life, Student Activities/Union Programs, Student Affairs, Student Commissaries, Students with Disabilities (Center for)).
  - Administrative records, 1980s, 1990; 1.0 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1998.0288_13)
    Subjects include: Faculty vitae (Administration (Miscellaneous), Agriculture and Natural Resources (College of), Business Administration (School of), Education (School of), Engineering (School of)).
  - Administrative records, 1980s, 1990; 1.0 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1998.0288_14)
    Subjects include: Faculty vitae (Engineering (School of), Fine Arts (School of), Law (School of), Liberal Arts and Sciences (College of), Nursing (School of), Pharmacy (School of), Social Work (School of)).
  - Administrative records, 1980s, 1990; 1.0 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs (Box 1998.0288_15)
    Subjects include: Faculty vitae (Liberal Arts and Sciences, College of).
  - Administrative records, publications, 1976, 1977-1984, 1980s, 1980-1983, 1983-1986, 1984-1987, 1985-1988, 1986-1989, 1987-1990, 1988-1991, 1989-1992, 1990, 1993; 1.0 Linear feet Some folders with labeled tabs (Box 1998.0288_16)
    Subjects include: Academic Planning, Faculty vitae (Administration (Regional Campuses), Hartford Campus, UConn Health Center), Mission Statements.
  - Administrative records, publications, 1977-1979, 1979-1995; 1.0 Linear feet Organized by subject (Box 1998.0288_17)
    Subjects include: Academic Planning (Departmental Program Profiles and Supplemental Information), Budget Program Profiles.
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, publications, 1982-1997, 1984-1997; 1.0 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs organized chronologically within subject (Box 1998.0288_18)
    Subjects include: Division of Student Affairs and Servives, Professional Staff Activites, Student Affairs documents and records.
  - Administrative records, correspondence, publications, 1973-1981, 1992-1997; 1.0 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs and binders organized chronologically within subject (Box 1998.0288_19)
    Subjects include: Division of Student Affairs and Services, Student Affairs documents and records, The University of Connecticut Chronicle.
  - Clippings, 1985-1988; 1.0 Linear feet Bound compilations (Box 1998.0288_20)
    Subjects include: UConn Newsclips compiled by Institutional Relations.
  - Clippings, 1988-1990; 1.0 Linear feet Bound compilations (Box 1998.0288_21)
  - Administrative records, correspondence, notes, publications, 1968-1985; 1.0 Linear feet Some folders with labeled tabs (Box 1998.0288_22)
    Subjects include: New England Board of Higher Education, Office of Institutional Research Resources.
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, publications, 1979-1990; 1.0 Linear feet Some folders with labeled tabs (Box 1998.0288_23)
  - Publications, 1977-2001; 1.0 Linear feet Publications in chronological order by fiscal year (Box 1998.0288_24)
    Subjects include: University of Connecticut Fact Book.
  - Publications, 1965, 1975-1983, 1977-1997; 1.0 Linear feet Publications in chronological order within subject (Box 1998.0288_25)
    Subjects include: American Council on Education, Educational Record: The Magazine of Higher Education, University of Connecticut Fact Book.
  - Financial records, publications, 1950, 1960-1977, 1984-1996; 1.0 Linear feet Publications/reports in chronological order within subject (Box 1998.0288_26)